<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources xmlns:tools="http://schemas.android.com/tools">
    <string name="app_name">Library Application</string>

    <!-- Book Descriptions -->
    <string name="book_great_gatsby_desc">About the Book Atomic Habits
Atomic Habits is written by the world-renowned behavioral expert James Clear. By reading this book, we learn how to easily form good habits and break bad ones. The strategies presented in the book are highly practical and universally applicable.

Through studying Atomic Habits and implementing its recommendations, we can transform both our business and lifestyle with ease. Guided by this book, we can successfully and permanently overcome bad habits such as overeating, procrastination, laziness, and even smoking, and move toward achieving any goal we set for ourselves.

James Clear presents an interesting theory. He states:

"If a person improves by just 1% every day, by the end of the year they will become 37 times better than they were at the beginning."
He also believes that our small, daily behaviors and habits determine where we will be in five years—how successful we become, or in what areas we might fail.

Regardless of how ambitious or advanced our goals may be, Atomic Habits helps us reach them by improving our daily performance.
Reading the English version of Atomic Habits not only allows us to benefit from the book’s insightful content and practical solutions for personal development, but also strengthens our English language proficiency.

</string>

    <string name="book_mockingbird_desc">Animal Farm Book
It must be acknowledged that Animal Farm requires little introduction. This satirical masterpiece delivers a powerful critique of the class-based structure of Soviet society and the authoritarian tendencies of Marxist ideologies. Written in a clear, fluent, and simple language, the book remains highly symbolic and controversial in its own right.

To date, Animal Farm has been translated into more than 70 languages, with millions of copies published by top-tier publishers worldwide.

George Orwell, the Author of Animal Farm
George Orwell, the author of this remarkable work, was born as Eric Blair in 1903 in India and passed away in 1950. Despite being an English teacher and at times a bookseller, Orwell had a deep understanding of human societies and political regimes, which is clearly reflected in his writings.</string>

    <string name="book_1984_desc">Summary of the Novel 1984

The story of this English novel takes place in the year 1984, in London—one of the cities of the superstate Oceania. The people of Oceania are divided into three classes: the working class, ordinary Party members, and the elite ranks of the Party. This nation is ruled by Big Brother (the Party leader and supreme overseer), a ruthless dictator. In this dystopian society, thinking freely, writing, falling in love, frowning, and similar acts are strictly forbidden. Anyone who breaks the law is swiftly executed.

The main character of the novel, Winston Smith, is an ordinary Party member. His job at the Ministry of Truth is to alter historical documents to fabricate new "truths." Disillusioned with Big Brother regime, Winston secretly acquires an old notebook. At first, he intends only to record his daily experiences, but he soon begins writing his thoughts. He even goes so far as to repeatedly write the phrase "Down with Big Brother" in the notebook.

Each of these acts is a grave offense—any one of them alone could lead to a death sentence. Winston does everything he can to ensure no one finds out he has a journal. However, he eventually notices that a dark-haired girl named Julia seems to be watching him. Fearing she might be a Party spy, Winston becomes anxious and paranoid. Then, one day, Julia secretly passes him a note that reads: "I love you."

This message marks the beginning of a thrilling and suspenseful relationship between Winston and Julia…

If you’d like to find out how the story unfolds, you can purchase the uncensored English version of 1984 from Zabanmehr Bookstore and enjoy both the gripping narrative and an opportunity to enhance your English language skills.</string>

    <string name="book_hobbit_desc">🌙 Twilight by Stephenie Meyer
Twilight is a captivating romantic fantasy novel—the first installment in a four-book series written by Stephenie Meyer
zabanmehrpub.com
+3
. Set in the gloomy, atmospheric town of Forks, Washington, the story follows Isabella “Bella” Swan, a teenage girl who moves to live with her father. There, she encounters the enigmatic and alluring Edward Cullen, a vampire whose mysterious charm leads to an intense and unconventional love story.

This unconventional romance explores themes of first love, danger, and the supernatural, as Bella becomes entwined in Edward’s immortal world filled with secret dangers and eternal devotion. The novel expertly blends teenage romance with supernatural suspense, ensuring an immersive read.

Zabanmehr Pub offers Twilight in a “digital print” format, originally priced at 550,000 Toman and currently available for 220,000 Toman. The edition weighs approximately 0.396 kg and is recorded with product code ZM‑1129</string>

    <string name="book_pride_prejudice_desc">The Shining (1977) is a masterful horror novel by Stephen King, set in the isolated Overlook Hotel in the Colorado Rockies during a harsh winter

The story follows Jack Torrance, a struggling writer and recovering alcoholic who becomes the hotel’s winter caretaker. He hopes the job will help him reconnect with his wife, Wendy, and their young son, Danny. However, the hotel harbors malevolent supernatural forces and deadly secrets

Danny, gifted with psychic abilities known as “the shining,” begins seeing horrific visions and sensing the Overlook’s evil

. Meanwhile, Jack increasingly loses control of his sanity and succumbs to the sinister influences lurking within the hotel walls

Beloved for its intense psychological suspense, The Shining is considered one of King’s definitive works and a pillar of modern horror literature
. It has inspired multiple adaptations, including Stanley Kubrick’s acclaimed 1980 film and a subsequent TV miniseries.</string>

    <string name="book_catcher_rye_desc">About the Novel Hunting Adeline 2 by H. D. Carlton

Hunting Adeline 2, written by H. D. Carlton, is a dark, mysterious romance novel that was published in 2021. This gripping sequel to Haunting Adeline continues the suspenseful and emotional journey that captivates readers with its intensity and depth.

Summary of Hunting Adeline 2

The story of Hunting Adeline revolves around three main characters: Adeline, Jack, and Calvin. Adeline, a young anthropologist, is determined to uncover the long-buried secrets of her familys past, which gradually leads her on a perilous and thrilling journey. Jack, a dark and enigmatic figure, enters Adelines life and assists her in unraveling the complex web of family mysteries.

</string>
    <string name="the_100_year_old" tools:ignore="StringEscaping">The 100-Year-Old Man Who Climbed Out the Window and Disappeared
The author of The 100-Year-Old Man Who Climbed Out the Window and Disappeared is Jonas Jonasson born in Sweden. After exploring various skills and professions such as journalism, he eventually struck luck and founded a successful television production company. However, not wanting to sacrifice his leisure time, he sold the company and moved to Switzerland with the significant wealth he had acquired. His debut novel was first published in 2009.

The title of the book is so intriguing that it immediately suggests an unconventional story. This sense is reinforced by the books dedication in which Jonasson writes: Those who only tell the truth are not worthy of having people listen to them

Summary of the Novel
The story is a humorous and absurd fictional biography of a 100-year-old man named Allan Karlsson. On his 100th birthday, Allan decides to escape from the retirement home and embarks on an unplanned journey. At a train station, he encounters a young man who asks him to watch over his large suitcase while he uses the restroom. However, the bus arrives before the young man returns, and Allan leaves with the suitcase, unintentionally starting an unexpected adventure.

Through a series of coincidental events, the author cleverly entangles the protagonist in historical incidents, allowing him to meet some of the most influential political figures of the 20th century — including Joseph Stalin, General Franco, Harry Truman, Winston Churchill, Mao Zedong, and Kim Il-sung. As Allan recounts his past, the reader is humorously taken through pivotal historical events such as the development of the atomic bomb, the Spanish Civil War, and the Chinese Revolution.

The 100-Year-Old Man Who Climbed Out the Window and Disappeared is a witty and entertaining novel that masterfully weaves humor with history and politics.</string>
    <string name="zamir" tools:ignore="StringEscaping">About the Novel Zamir
Zamir is a contemporary Turkish novel suitable for readers aged 12 and up
The paperback edition weighs approximately 0.495kg and is packaged as a softcover
Although specific details such as the author and plot are not provided, this edition—packaged under the code ZM‑337321—offers an engaging reading experience, as indicated by its presence in Zabanmehr’s collection
.</string>
    <string name="the_good_terrorist" tools:ignore="StringEscaping">The Good Terrorist — Doris Lessing (1985)
Genre and Background
The Good Terrorist is a political novel by British author Doris Lessing, drawing inspiration from the 1983 Harrods bombing in London
It was shortlisted for the Booker Prize and received the WH Smith Literary Award and the Mondello Prize
Premise and Main Character
The story centers on Alice, a naïve, idealistic woman in her mid-thirties who joins a small group of political radicals squatting in a derelict London house. While she sees herself as a revolutionary fighting “fascist imperialism,” Alice is also deeply maternal, taking responsibility for the communal living space and its occupants
Plot Highlights
As the group experiments with bomb-making and plans an attack, Alice reluctantly goes along. A tragic disaster occurs when an explosive prematurely detonates, killing one of their own and bystanders. Alice must then confront her role in the action and the realization that she has become a terrorist .
Themes and Style
The novel is both satirical and darkly humorous, exploring the contradictions between Alice’s nurturing instincts and her involvement in political violence
. Critics describe it as a character study rather than a straightforward political tract, using irony to examine self-styled revolutionaries in affluent societies
en.wikipedia.org
.</string>

    <string name="brief_questions" tools:ignore="StringEscaping">Book: Brief Answers to the Big Questions

Brief Answers to the Big Questions is a popular science book authored by the renowned physicist Stephen Hawking. This book was published posthumously by Hodder and Stoughton in the UK, following Professor Hawking’s death. In his final work, Hawking explores some of the greatest mysteries of our universe, and as expected by his admirers, he reaffirms his scientific perspective that the best solution to Earths challenges lies in science.

The book responds to some of the most profound questions of our modern age. Hawking discusses his discoveries and views on everything from the origin of the universe to black holes and the importance of space colonization. He also warns about the potential dangers of artificial intelligence. The book is divided into four main sections:

Why are we here now?

Will we survive?

Will technology save us or destroy us?

What is the secret to our success?

Stephen Hawking
Undoubtedly, Stephen Hawking is considered the most famous physicist of our time, who passed away not long ago. A tireless scientist, he was seen as a symbol of resilience and perseverance. Despite being diagnosed with ALS (motor neuron disease), he spent more than forty years of his life in a wheelchair. As he once said, he was fortunate that the only part of his body that remained functional was his brain
.</string>
    <string name="powerless" tools:ignore="StringEscaping">Review of the Book Powerless
Powerless, written by Lauren Roberts, is one of the newest additions to the fantasy and science fiction genre. This gripping novel tells the story of a girl named Paedyn (originally referred to as Nova in your translation), who lives in a world divided into two groups: the "Empowered" and the "Powerless." Paedyn, as one of the powerless, struggles in a society where those with extraordinary abilities dominate and control others.

Summary of the Story
The protagonist, Paedyn, is a teenage girl born without the special powers that many others around her possess. She lives in a harsh society where supernatural powers determine status and authority, forcing the powerless to hide their weaknesses and conform to survive. Feeling out of place and disconnected from the world around her, Paedyn embarks on a journey to find her own identity and carve out a place where she truly belongs.

</string>
    <string name="crenshaw" tools:ignore="StringEscaping">
        Introduction to the Book Crenshaw
Crenshaw is a contemporary fantasy novel written by Katherine Applegate, first published in 2017. This English-language book explores significant social issues such as poverty, homelessness, and friendship through the eyes of a ten-year-old boy named Jackson.

Summary of Crenshaw
Jackson and his family are facing serious financial difficulties and are on the verge of becoming homeless. In the midst of this challenging time, an old imaginary friend named Crenshaw reappears in Jackson’s life. Crenshaw is a large, humanlike cat who not only comforts Jackson during these difficult moments but also helps him confront his emotions and anxieties about his familys financial situation.
</string>
    <string name="bable" tools:ignore="StringEscaping">
        Summary of the Novel Babel

Babel tells the story of Robin Swift, a Cantonese boy who is orphaned at a young age and brought to Britain by a mysterious English professor. In Oxford, Robin studies linguistics and translation, eventually joining the magical world of Babel, the Royal Institute of Translation at Oxford.

As Robin delves deeper into his studies, he gradually uncovers the dark truth behind the silver-based magic that powers Babel. He comes to realize that this magic is deeply intertwined with British imperialism and colonial exploitation. Faced with a moral dilemma, Robin must choose between remaining loyal to his friends and mentors at Babel, or rising up against the very system that sustains their power.

Babel is a thought-provoking and politically charged novel that explores the intersection of language, power, and resistance in a richly imagined historical fantasy setting.
</string>
    <string name="the_grate_gasby" tools:ignore="StringEscaping">
        Introduction to The Great Gatsby

The Great Gatsby is one of the most influential and best-selling American novels, written by F. Scott Fitzgerald, a renowned American author. It is his third novel, originally published in 1925 by Charles Scribner’s Sons. Interestingly, the book was not initially well-received and its first edition was considered a commercial failure.

However, after Fitzgeralds death, the novel was republished in 1954, and this time, it gained widespread recognition and acclaim. Readers began to appreciate its literary depth, and it soon became one of the most celebrated novels in American literature, eventually securing a spot among the Top 100 American Novels of All Time.

Set in the Jazz Age, The Great Gatsby explores the disillusionment of the American Dream, portraying themes such as corruption, consumerism, and the moral decay behind the façade of wealth and glamour in 1920s America.

Due to its profound narrative and cultural impact, the novel has been adapted into several films. One of the most notable adaptations is the 2013 film The Great Gatsby starring Leonardo DiCaprio, who played the role of Jay Gatsby with critical acclaim.

This timeless classic continues to captivate readers with its poetic prose, tragic romance, and powerful commentary on ambition and identity.
</string>
    <string name="the_giver_of_stars" tools:ignore="StringEscaping">
        Introduction to The Giver of Stars

The Giver of Stars is the latest and one of the most significant works by Jojo Moyes, a bestselling English author. This novel stands out as one of the most compelling stories about women, portraying themes of love, compassion, and self-awareness within a society facing decline. Based on a true story, it was nominated in 2019 for the Goodreads Choice Award for Best Novel of the Year.

About Jojo Moyes
Jojo Moyes is a 50-year-old English writer who began her career as a journalist before turning to romantic fiction in 2002. She has won the Romantic Novel of the Year award twice. Her debut novel was Sheltering Rain, but she is best known globally for Me Before You, After You, and The Last Letter from Your Lover.

About the Book
The Giver of Stars is inspired by real events and tells the story set during the economic hardships in the United States, specifically in Kentucky. The narrative revolves around a group of young women who challenge conventional thinking and strive to break free from the monotony of daily life. They bring knowledge, new perspectives, strength, and hope to their community.

The protagonists are five women who quickly become beloved characters, reminiscent of Lou Clark from Me Before You. Among them is Margery, a smart and independent woman who leads the group and soon becomes a close friend and ally to Alice. Later, three more single women join their team, known as the “Pack Horse Librarians of Kentucky.” Their mission is to deliver books to people who have never had access to them and to remind their community of truths that can transform lives.

The Giver of Stars has also been adapted into a film directed by Thomas Bezucha, highlighting its broad appeal and impact.

This novel celebrates female friendship, resilience, and the power of literature to change lives, making it a deeply inspiring and memorable read.
</string>
    <string name="the_alchemist" tools:ignore="StringEscaping">
        Introduction to The Alchemist

If you have reached a good level in English and want to improve it through reading and translating stories, the famous and successful novel The Alchemist by the beloved author Paulo Coelho is an excellent choice to start with.

This captivating story illustrates the inner human desire to soar freely and break away from attachments. Since its first publication in 1988 in Portuguese, the novel has sold over two million copies worldwide.

Paulo Coelho’s masterpiece tells the magical tale of Santiago, an Andalusian shepherd boy who embarks on a journey in search of a worldly treasure. Along the way, he must let go of his attachments and face various challenges. Santiago’s experiences teach us the importance of always following our dreams and listening to the voice of our hearts.

As Coelho mentioned, he wrote The Alchemist in just two weeks. He explained that the story had already been written in his soul beforehand.

The central theme of the book revolves around discovering one’s destiny. Santiago, the protagonist, is advised that "when you really want something, all the universe conspires in helping you to achieve it." The core of this allegorical novel is philosophical, woven throughout the narrative.

The Alchemist emphasizes that human perfection is reached when all beings strive to fulfill their personal dreams and become the best versions of themselves.

The book also highlights fear as one of the main obstacles to achieving personal dreams. Therefore, if you are looking for a book that inspires and motivates you to pursue your highest goals, The Alchemist is highly recommended. Do not miss this fascinating read!
</string>
    <string name="a_little_life" tools:ignore="StringEscaping">
        Summary of A Little Life

A Little Life follows the lives of four close friends—Jude, Willem, JB, and Malcolm—who remain connected from their college years through middle age in New York City. The central character, Jude, is a successful but enigmatic lawyer burdened by a dark and painful past.

Jude struggles with profound physical and emotional trauma, and throughout the novel, we witness his efforts to overcome these challenges in search of peace and happiness. The book deeply explores themes of human relationships, love, friendship, loss, and hope, offering a powerful and moving portrayal of the complexities of life.

</string>
    <string name="halmet" tools:ignore="StringEscaping">
        Summary and Significance of Hamlet

Hamlet, written by William Shakespeare, is a timeless masterpiece and one of the most celebrated plays in literary history. Composed in the late 16th century, its enduring popularity stems from its profound exploration of human nature, morality, and existential themes, as well as Shakespeare’s unparalleled poetic and dramatic craft.

The story begins with Prince Hamlet of Denmark returning from Germany to his home in Elsinore Castle to attend his father’s funeral. The death of King Hamlet is shrouded in mystery, and no one knows the true circumstances behind the king’s suspicious demise. Amid this uncertainty, Hamlet discovers that his mother has quickly remarried his uncle Claudius, who now occupies the throne—and that they are intimately involved.

Hamlet’s doubts and inner turmoil intensify when the ghost of his deceased father appears, revealing that Claudius murdered him. The ghost implores Hamlet to avenge this treacherous and brutal crime. This revelation sets in motion a complex drama of revenge, madness, political intrigue, and philosophical reflection.

Hamlet remains influential because it deeply examines themes such as betrayal, revenge, morality, the nature of existence, and the complexity of the human psyche, which continue to resonate with audiences worldwide.
</string>
    <!-- Book Titles -->
    <string name="book_great_gatsby">The Great Gatsby</string>
    <string name="book_mockingbird">To Kill a Mockingbird</string>
    <string name="book_1984">1984</string>
    <string name="book_hobbit">The Hobbit</string>
    <string name="book_pride_prejudice">Pride and Prejudice</string>
    <string name="book_catcher_rye">The Catcher in the Rye</string>

    <!-- Book Authors -->
    <string name="author_fitzgerald">F. Scott Fitzgerald</string>
    <string name="author_lee">Harper Lee</string>
    <string name="author_orwell">George Orwell</string>
    <string name="author_tolkien">J.R.R. Tolkien</string>
    <string name="author_austen">Jane Austen</string>
    <string name="author_salinger">J.D. Salinger</string>
</resources>